<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Luo Mai</title>
    <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://luomai.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 13:35:37 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://luomai.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>[10/24, Grant] Secured a prestigious ARIA grant with Imperial College &amp; Cambridge University.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-aria-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-aria-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am deeply honored to receive a prestigious grant from the Advanced Research + Invention Agency (ARIA) to develop a scalable and modular performance simulation framework for emerging AI models, systems, and hardware. This project will be co-led by Imperial (Aaron Zhao), Edinburgh (Luo Mai), and Cambridge (Robert Mullins), bringing together over 10 world-leading experts across the entire system stack. With this £4.5M funding, we will build a critical mass of talent and skills to incubate game-changing AI systems, enabling a 1000X improvement in AI&amp;rsquo;s efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aria.org.uk/scaling-compute/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;official announcement&lt;/a&gt; from ARIA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[10/24, Paper] Tenplex, the first elastic LLM system, accepted to SOSP 2024.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-tenplex-sosp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-tenplex-sosp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tenplex is a new system enabling elastic training of LLMs with advanced multi-dimensional parallelism. The Tenplex paper has been accepted for presentation at the 30th Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP’24). We are currently preparing to open-source the project. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[07/24, Student Achievement] Congrats to Yao Fu on Winning 2024 Rising Star in ML &amp; Systems.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-risingstar-yao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-risingstar-yao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year’s Rising Stars cohort includes 41 junior researchers from 33 institutions globally. Selected from over 170 applicants, Yao is the sole recipient from the UK and one of three from Europe, the other two European students coming from ETH, Zurich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2024 Rising Start workshop was held in the NVIDIA HQ in Santa Clara, CA in July, where Yao presented his research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yao is a third-year PhD student in Computer Science at The University of Edinburgh, supervised by Dr Luo Mai. His research lies at the intersection of machine learning and systems, focusing on performance and affordability. Recently, his work has centred on efficient serving systems for large language models, leading to two main projects: ServerlessLLM and the MoESys Leaderboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the coverage from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://informatics.ed.ac.uk/news-events/news/latest-news/informatics-student-among-machine-learning-and-systems-rising-stars&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;our school&lt;/a&gt; and the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mlcommons.org/2024/06/2024-mlc-rising-stars/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;annoucement from MLCommon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[07/24, Paper] ServerlessLLM, the first serverless LLM system, accepted to OSDI 2024.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-serverlessllm-osdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-serverlessllm-osdi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ServerlessLLM is a new system enabling cost-effective serverless inference for LLMs by implementing a scalable and high-performance “checkpoint storage layer” on GPU servers. It achieves this through an innovative LLM checkpoint format, a multi-tier checkpoint loading subsystem, an efficient live migration algorithm, and a locality-friendly GPU serverless architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ServerlessLLM paper has been accepted to the top systems conference, OSDI’24, and we are preparing to open-source the project. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[05/24, Award] Win a Microsoft Research Startrack Scholar Award.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-startrack-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-startrack-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am thrilled to receive the Microsoft Research Startrack Scholar Award, a prestigious honor for young faculty in the field of computer science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[03/24, Grant] Secured funds from EPSRC and industry partners to build a CDT for ML Systems.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-mlsyscdt-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-mlsyscdt-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am deeply thrilled to have secured an EPSRC grant (£8.7M) matched with £9.2M from industry partners to establish a Centre for Doctoral Training (CDT) in ML Systems. This grant is co-led by Amos Storkey (PI), Mike O&amp;rsquo;Boyle (co-I), Ajitha Rajan (co-I), and myself (co-I). With this CDT, we are one of the few places in the world capable of creating the critical mass of talent, skills, and resources needed to incubate game-changing technologies for ML systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this CDT, PhD students will have the opportunity to build expertise across the entire AI system stack—spanning models, algorithms, software, hardware, and large-scale clusters. The CDT is supported by UK EPSRC and over 20 industry partners, with that number still growing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ukri.org/what-we-do/developing-people-and-skills/epsrc/studentships/centres-for-doctoral-training/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;announcement 1&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gow.epsrc.ukri.org/NGBOViewGrant.aspx?GrantRef=EP/Y03516X/1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;announcement 2&lt;/a&gt; from EPSRC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[12/23, Paper &amp; Award] TorchOpt is accepted by JMLR and becomes a PyTorch Ecosystem Project.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/23-torchopt-jmlr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/23-torchopt-jmlr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 2 years incubation, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/metaopt/torchopt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TorchOpt&lt;/a&gt; has become a PyTorch Ecosystem Project 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/pytorch/introducing-torchopt-a-high-performance-differentiable-optimization-library-for-pytorch-37c4c0ef6ae1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Announcement&lt;/a&gt;. Its paper is also accepted by the JMLR in the open-source software track.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[10/23, Award] Finalist for the Chancellor&#39;s Rising Star in Research.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/23-rising-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/23-rising-star/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am nominated by the school for a Chancellor&amp;rsquo;s Rising Star in Research Award, a prestigious honour for young faculty joined University of Edinburgh between 2018 and 2023. The nomination passes highly-selective panels at the school and the college level, and becomes a finalist for the university level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[09/23, Paper] GEAR, a new training system for bridging RL and LLMs, accepted to ICML 2023.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/23-gear-icml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/23-gear-icml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gear system to appear in ICML 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[07/22, Paper] Ekko, the first system unifying training and inference, accepted to OSDI 2022</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/22-ekko-osdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/22-ekko-osdi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Paper &amp;ldquo;Ekko: A Large-Scale Deep Learning Recommender System with Low-Latency Model Update&amp;rdquo; is accepted by USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI) 2022. OSDI brings together professionals from academic and industrial backgrounds in what has become a premier forum for discussing the design, implementation, and implications of systems software. The symposium emphasizes innovative research as well as quantified or insightful experiences in systems design and implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MegBA library in ECCV 2022</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/22-megba-eccv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/22-megba-eccv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Paper &amp;ldquo;MegBA: A GPU-Based Distributed Library for Large-Scale Bundle Adjustment&amp;rdquo; is accepted by ECCV 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cameo system in NSDI 2021</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/21-cameo-accept-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 13:45:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/21-cameo-accept-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Paper &amp;ldquo;Move Fast and Meet Deadlines: Fine-grained Real-time Stream Processing with Cameo&amp;rdquo; is accepted by USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI) 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSDI focuses on the design principles, implementation, and practical evaluation of networked and distributed systems. Its goal is to bring together researchers from across the networking and systems community to foster a broad approach to addressing overlapping research challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSDI provides a high-quality forum for presenting results and discussing ideas that further the knowledge and understanding of the networked systems community as a whole, continue a significant research dialog, or push the architectural boundaries of network services.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KungFu system in OSDI 2020</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/20-kungfu-accept-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/20-kungfu-accept-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Paper &amp;ldquo;KungFu: Making Training in Distributed Machine Learning Adaptive&amp;rdquo; is accepted by USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI) 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OSDI brings together professionals from academic and industrial backgrounds in what has become a premier forum for discussing the design, implementation, and implications of systems software. The symposium emphasizes innovative research as well as quantified or insightful experiences in systems design and implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk in the AI systems workshop at SOSP 2019</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/19-talk-sosp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 13:53:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/19-talk-sosp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am invited to give a talk: &amp;ldquo;Adaptive Distributed Training of Deep Learning Models&amp;rdquo; in the Workshop on AI Systems at ACM Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP) 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
