<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Luo Mai</title>
    <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://luomai.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 13:35:37 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://luomai.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tenplex in SOSP 2024.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-tenplex-sosp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-tenplex-sosp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tenplex is a new system enabling elastic training of LLMs with advanced multi-dimensional parallelism. The Tenplex paper has been accepted for presentation at the 30th Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP’24). We are currently preparing to open-source the project. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trilled to receive Microsoft Research Startrack Scholar Award.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-startrack-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-startrack-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am thrilled to receive the Microsoft Research Startrack Scholar Award, a prestigious honor for young faculty in the field of computer science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ServerlessLLM in OSDI 2024.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-serverlessllm-osdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/24-serverlessllm-osdi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ServerlessLLM is a new system enabling cost-effective serverless inference for LLMs by implementing a scalable and high-performance “checkpoint storage layer” on GPU servers. It achieves this through an innovative LLM checkpoint format, a multi-tier checkpoint loading subsystem, an efficient live migration algorithm, and a locality-friendly GPU serverless architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ServerlessLLM paper has been accepted to the top systems conference, OSDI’24, and we are preparing to open-source the project. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TorchOpt becomes a PyTorch Ecosystem Project, and its paper gets in JMLR 2023.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/23-torchopt-jmlr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/23-torchopt-jmlr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 2 years incubation, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/metaopt/torchopt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TorchOpt&lt;/a&gt; has become a PyTorch Ecosystem Project 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/pytorch/introducing-torchopt-a-high-performance-differentiable-optimization-library-for-pytorch-37c4c0ef6ae1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Announcement&lt;/a&gt;. Its paper is also accepted by the JMLR in the open-source software track.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trilled to be nominated for the Chancellor&#39;s Rising Star in Research.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/23-rising-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/23-rising-star/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am nominated by the school for a Chancellor&amp;rsquo;s Rising Star in Research Award, a prestigious honour for young faculty joined University of Edinburgh between 2018 and 2023. The nomination passes highly-selective panels at the school and the college level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gear library in ICML 2023.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/23-gear-icml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/23-gear-icml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gear system to appear in ICML 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ekko system in OSDI 2022</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/22-ekko-osdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/22-ekko-osdi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Paper &amp;ldquo;Ekko: A Large-Scale Deep Learning Recommender System with Low-Latency Model Update&amp;rdquo; is accepted by USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI) 2022. OSDI brings together professionals from academic and industrial backgrounds in what has become a premier forum for discussing the design, implementation, and implications of systems software. The symposium emphasizes innovative research as well as quantified or insightful experiences in systems design and implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MegBA library in ECCV 2022</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/22-megba-eccv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/22-megba-eccv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Paper &amp;ldquo;MegBA: A GPU-Based Distributed Library for Large-Scale Bundle Adjustment&amp;rdquo; is accepted by ECCV 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta RL paper in NeruIPS 2022.</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/22-metarl-nips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/22-metarl-nips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meta RL paper to appear in NeurIPS 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KungFu system in OSDI 2020</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/20-kungfu-accept-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 13:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/20-kungfu-accept-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Paper &amp;ldquo;KungFu: Making Training in Distributed Machine Learning Adaptive&amp;rdquo; is accepted by USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI) 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OSDI brings together professionals from academic and industrial backgrounds in what has become a premier forum for discussing the design, implementation, and implications of systems software. The symposium emphasizes innovative research as well as quantified or insightful experiences in systems design and implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cameo system in NSDI 2021</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/21-cameo-accept-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 13:45:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/21-cameo-accept-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Paper &amp;ldquo;Move Fast and Meet Deadlines: Fine-grained Real-time Stream Processing with Cameo&amp;rdquo; is accepted by USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI) 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSDI focuses on the design principles, implementation, and practical evaluation of networked and distributed systems. Its goal is to bring together researchers from across the networking and systems community to foster a broad approach to addressing overlapping research challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSDI provides a high-quality forum for presenting results and discussing ideas that further the knowledge and understanding of the networked systems community as a whole, continue a significant research dialog, or push the architectural boundaries of network services.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk in the AI systems workshop at SOSP 2019</title>
      <link>https://luomai.github.io/post/19-talk-sosp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 13:53:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luomai.github.io/post/19-talk-sosp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am invited to give a talk: &amp;ldquo;Adaptive Distributed Training of Deep Learning Models&amp;rdquo; in the Workshop on AI Systems at ACM Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP) 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
